

# DAVID MIN TAT GOY

Full Stack Web Developer/Engineer

Site: <u>davidgoy.github.io</u> Projects: <u>github.com/davidgoy</u> | Email: <u>david@davidgoy.dev</u>

### **Summary**

Australian web developer living in Guernsey, Channel Islands. Skilled in developing LAMP stack web applications. Built a number of SaaS over the years, from architecture to deployment. Founder of an electric vehicle startup. PhD research degree dropout.

# **Technologies**

- Proficient in LAMP stack
  - Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Bootstrap
  - Back-end: PHP, MySQL and CodeIgniter
  - o Shell scripting: Bash
- Knowledgeable in full-stack JS
  - o Front-end: Vue.js
  - Back-end: Node.js, Express and MongoDB
- · Knowledgeable in hosting environment setup and maintenance
  - o OS: Linux
  - Web server: Apache HTTP Server

## **Projects**

- Reflect (<a href="https://github.com/davidgoy/reflect">https://github.com/davidgoy/reflect</a>)
   SSR and static site generation capable web app that acts as the front-end for your headless WordPress.
- Reflect Form Mailer (<a href="https://github.com/davidgoy/reflect-form-mailer">https://github.com/davidgoy/reflect-form-mailer</a>)
   Addon for Reflect. Automatically makes plain HTML forms submittable.

### **Awards**

- US patent 8612100 for invention of vehicle management control system (2013)
  - Invented during time as a PhD research student at The University of Sydney
  - Enables an entire vehicle to be controlled by a single software framework running on macOS, Linux or Windows computer
- The NEC Semiconductors Singapore Pte. Ltd. Award for Best Project Work (2000)
  - Created during time as a Diploma in Mechatronics Engineering student at Nanyang Polytechnic, Singapore
  - Software written in C that enabled engineers to simulate the dynamic performance of micromouse robot without having to build a physical prototype

### Businesses

Full-stack Web Developer/Engineer (2011 - Now)
 Min Tat Gov (sole trader)

• Founder (2006 - 2013)

Goy Advanced Automobile

Australian electric vehicle startup. Joined by more than 10 Australian and international team members. The startup did not succeed. However:

- Successfully raised first round of funds to pay for consultation with Lotus Engineering
- Vehicle designed by team was featured in *Top Gear Australia* magazine, *Auto Salon* magazine, *Sydney Morning Herald* newspaper and *The Age* (Melbourne) newspaper

# **Employment**

• Technical Delivery and Support - Applications (2018 - Now)
States of Guernsey then later at Agilisys Guernsey

Provides technical support for a wide range of applications used by various departments of the States of Guernsey (i.e. the government of the Bailiwick of Guernsey, Channel Islands)

Manufacturing Engineer (2004 - 2007)
 Silverbrook Research Pty. Ltd., Australia

Researched and implemented mass production methods that could be potentially used to manufacture an ultra-high speed printhead developed by the company

### **Achievements**

- Developed a solution to clean one of the key components that improved the part's yield from approx. 50% to nearly 100% at the cleaning stage of the manufacturing process
- Improvised a solution to remove unwanted residue from a key component's coating, increasing yield from approx. 8% to 90% at an important stage of the manufacturing process and resulting in significant time and cost savings
- Associate Engineer (2000 2001)

Chartered Semiconductor Manufacturing Ltd., Singapore

### Lithography/process department:

Troubleshoot process and machine related issues in the production line, performed quality checks on silicon wafers and develop strategies to minimise defects/increase manufacturing yield

### IPM layout/test structure department:

Drafted semiconductor structures using CAD tool for new test module designs

#### **Achievements**

- <u>Lithography/process department:</u>
  - Successfully implemented new program criteria for automatic defect detection using Scanning Electron Microscope, significantly reducing errors/false alarms and thus production down time by approx. one hour per day
- IPM layout/test structure department:
   Developed software that automated the drafting of semiconductor structures, enabling the department to produce a month's worth of component design drawings in less than five hours

#### Education

- Doctor of Philosophy (Engineering and IT) by Research Withdrawn (Dropped out 2013 to pursue business)
   The University of Sydney
- Bachelor of Engineering (Materials and Mechanical Systems) with Honours (2004)

The Australian National University

- Faculty of Engineering and IT Student Services First Year International Scholarship (2002)
- Diploma in Information Technology (Website Development) With Distinction (2011)

TAFE NSW

- 26 distinctions
- Diploma in Engineering (Mechatronics) with Merit (2000)

Nanyang Polytechnic, Singapore

- 15 distinctions
- Top 10% of the graduating cohort for the diploma course
- Sponsorship under Chartered Semiconductor Manufacturing Ltd. (1999 2000)
- Top Student Award, Mechatronics Engineering (1999/2000)
- Top Student Award, Mechatronics Engineering (1998/1999)